SAGARIKA SARDESAI

LinkedIn: /sagarikasardesai | Tableau: /sagarikasardesai | GitHub: /sagarikasardesai | Website: sagarikasardesai.github.io sagarikasardesai13@gmail.com | 6199537007 | Open to Relocation

ABOUT ME

An MS Data Science student with prior experience in Business Analysis and Software Engineering, where I extracted meaningful insights for informed decision-making. Actively searching for Data Analysis/Science roles. Some of my relevant coursework: Data Management for Data Science, Probability & Statistics, Statistical Models, Machine Learning & Fraud Analytics.

EDUCATION

MS, Data Science San Diego, CA UC San Diego, CGPA 3.90 Sep 2022 - Jun 2024

Btech, Computer Science and Engineering

Vellore Institute of Technology, CGPA 8.61 Jul 2016 - Jun 2020

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Research Assistant

San Diego, CA

Vellore, India

UC San Diego

May 2023 - Nov 2023

- Ensured data accuracy by 5% through cleaning, exploration (pandas, numpy), and visualization (matplotlib, seaborn) in the Data Quality Report, revealing significant patterns and trends.
- Utilized exploratory data analysis, statistical analysis, and NLP techniques (nltk, transformers) such as VADER and ROBERTa (LLM) to measure sentiments and derive meaningful conclusions about consumer behavior.
- Derived valuable insights into consumer attitudes and decision-making regarding End-of-life choices.

Business Analyst Pune, India Credit Suisse May 2021 - Jun 2022

• Analyzed 80,000+ production and test data records sourced from company databases and software using SQL and Advanced

- **Excel** for defect mitigation.
- Performed ad-hoc analysis to support business strategy, reported & delivered actionable insights to cross-functional teams.
- Identified root causes, patterns, and trends by conducting 300+ SWIFT CSDR Test Trades (Hold & Release), resulting in a 70% decrease in defects and unveiling new product development areas.
- Created 300+ functional & user acceptance test (UAT) Quality Assurance (QA) B2B scenarios in HP-ALM.
- Led defect management processes to streamline the SWIFT trade lifecycle business processes.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Investment Scope of SBIR Awarded Companies

- Conducted in-depth analysis of the SBIR Awarded Companies containing 165,000+ records using Python and PostgreSQL, revealing patterns in industry sectors and year-wise award amounts across US agencies and branches.
- Improved data accuracy by 20% by cleaning methods including data type adjustments, keyword extraction, and imputation.
- Established relationships between US departments and agencies using Cypher (Neo4j) graphs, to enhance analysis context.
- Web scraped (Beautify Soup, Selenium Webdriver) recent news (Python data pipeline for ETL) about relevant companies, stored in MongoDB for further reference.

Covid19 Data exploration and Visualization

- Utilized PostgreSQL to analyze the OWID Covid-19 Dataset of 85,000+ rows, identifying patterns in global infection and mortality counts, country-specific statistics, and regional peak counts.
- Forecasted infection numbers for highly affected countries and presented insights visually with Tableau to aid decision-making.

Predictive Analysis for Detecting Credit Card Transaction Fraud

- Utilized supervised machine learning to detect credit card fraud, resulting in estimated savings of 21M USD with a 3% FDR.
- Tuned, trained, tested and compared performance of Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, LGBM, LGBM with SMOTE, MLP classifier, Gradient Boosting Classifier, CatBoost, XGBoost, SVM.
- Analyzed 90,000+ credit card transactions, conducting data exploration, cleaning, and visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn) to uncover insights.
- Feature engineered ((pandas, numpy, scikit-learn) over 1000 variables and selected (mlxtend, lightgbm) from existing dataset fields for comprehensive analysis.
- Employed the Kolmogorov-Smirnov statistical test to feature select 20-25 relevant variables reducing training time by 30%, improving model accuracy and fraud detection capabilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, Python, R, Cypher, PySpark, SparkSQL

Data Vis and BI Tools: Tableau, Qlik Sense, Advanced Excel (Advanced Formulas, XLOOKUP, VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables, Stat tools, Macros, Charts)

Cloud Technologies: AWS (Redshift, Glue, S3)

Other: Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Anaconda, Git (Version Control), Jira, Confluence